0450 911 601

Kennethcdlc@gmail.com



Permanent Resident

github.com/kendlc/

linkedin.com/in/kennethcdlc/

in

kendlcdev.netlify.app/

# 

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

**DELA CRUZ** 

KENNETH

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Tooezy | Jan 2023 - Present **Software Engineer**

- Implements full-stack development using Typescript, ReactJS, NextJS, React Native, Cypress, Node.js, Parse Platform, and MongoDB.
- Develops and maintains responsive web applications, while also specializing in the design and optimization of cross-platform mobile applications.
- Implements server-side logic using Node.js and maintained databases for optimal performance.
- Manages relational and non-relational databases, ensuring data integrity and security.
- Collaborates with dev team to establish continuous integration and deployment pipelines.

## SUBI | July 2022 - Jan 2023 **Junior Software Engineer**

- Utilised Typescript, Node.js, React Native, Parse Platform and MongoDB in full stack mobile development.
- Designed, coded and debuged software product.
- Maintained and improved existing codebases.
- Worked with the business to implement new product features and functionality in a fast paced agile environment.

## General Assembly | 2022

### **Software Engineer**

Participated in a rigorous 12-week, 480+ hour intensive program focused on comprehensive learning of essential full-stack software development concepts. The program concluded with milestone projects, where I applied the acquired fundamentals in practical applications.

- Project 3: Pokemon Quizzr | Github | Live Site
- Project 2: Expense Trackr | Github | Live Site
- Project 1: Manga-shoppu | Github | Live Site
- Project 0: Tic Tac Toe | Github | Live Site

#### Canva | 2019-2022

#### **Junior Chef**

Utilised Stakeholder management and communication skills to ensure a positive customer experience.

# **Dream Makers Construction | 2015-2017 Field Electrical Engineer**

- Managed costs and resources to meet construction budget.
- Designed revisions and additional works using AutoCAD.
- Identified labour and material cost revisions on electrical works.

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a software engineer passionate on problem solving and constant learning. With years of experience in electrical engineering and hospitality, I get to transfer my critical thinking, problem solving and creativity skills into the everchanging field of software engineering.

## **PROFESSIONAL** SKILLS

Node.JS HTML / CSS •

MongoDB . JavaScript •

Ruby on Rails TypeScript •

> Firebase • React.JS •

PostgreSQL Next.JS •

RESTful API React Native •

Cypress • Redux.JS •

Netlify • Ruby •

Render • Bootstrap •

> Git • Material UI •

#### **EDUCATION**

2022

**Software Engineering Immersive** 

General Assembly

2018-2019

**Master of Project Management Graduate Certificate in Information Technology** 

Central Queensland University

2010 - 2015 Bachelor of Science in **Electrical Engineering** 

**Bulacan State University** 







